Guide to the Gotham Inc. Records, 1967-1997 and undated RL.00468
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Materials, 1973-1996 and undated, 129 boxes
  - Small Clients, 1975-1996 and undated
    - McDonald's, 1987-1994
      - 2072. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. McDonald's. 7 spots. See Enclosed List. 1991 (Box 123)
      - 2073. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. McDonald's. 8 spots. See Enclosed List. 1991 (Box 123)
      - 2074. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. McDonald's. 7 spots. See Enclosed List. 1991 (Box 123)
      - 2075. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. McDonald's. Frybenders :30. 1992 (Box 123)
      - 2076. McDonald's. MCLN 1013 Gravedale High; Gravedale High $1.99. 1992 (Box 123)
      - 2077. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. McDonald's. New Business Reel. 1994 (Box 123)
    - Maybelline, 1994-1995
      - 2078. Maybelline. Natural Defense Makeup. Maybe it's You 2 :30. 1994 (Box 123)
      - 2079. Gotham Inc. Maybelline. WPMW 5013 French Kiss :30. 1995 (Box 123)
    - Maybelline (continued), 1995 (Box 124)
      - 2080. Maybelline. 5 spots. See Enclosed List. 1995 (Box 124)
      - 2081. Gotham Inc. Maybelline. WPMW 5013 French Kiss :30. 1995 (Box 124)
      - 2082. Maybelline. Comments :30 Cut 4 (candlelight). 1995 (Box 124)
      - 2083. Gotham Inc. Maybelline. WPMW 5013 French Kiss :30. 1995 (Box 124)
      - 2084. Maybelline.Dailirs Dab of Product. Undated (Box 124)
    - Rydelle Labs, 1984-1985
      - 2085. Momar. Rydelle Labs. Fiberall Without the Sugar :30. 1984 (Box 124)
      - 2086. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Rydelle Labs. Zact Toothpaste. RLZ 4033 Close-up/Mouth :30. 1984 (Box 124)
      - 2087. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Rydelle Labs. Zact Toothpaste. RLZ 4023 Mouth. 1984 (Box 124)
      - 2088. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Fiberall. Better Tasting Way Animatic :30. Undated (Box 124)
      - 2089. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Rydelle Labs. JSFI 5063 Fiberall/Fiberwafer :30; JSFI 5073 Better Tasting Way :30. 1985 (Box 124)
      - 2090. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Rydelle Labs. Fiber Wafers. JSFW 5275 Wafer :15. 1985 (Box 124)
      - 2091. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Rydelle Labs. Fiberall. JSFI 5113 Why did you Switch Rev.1 :30. 1985 (Box 124)
      - 2092. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Rydelle Labs. Fiberall Power. JSFI 5155 Why did you Switch Vers.II :15. 1985 (Box 124)
      - 2093. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Rydelle Labs. Zact Toothpaste. JSZA 5063 If you do This :30. 1985 (Box 124)
      - 2094. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Rydelle Labs. Zact. JSZA 5105 Do you do this Rev.1 :15; JSZA 5083 Do you do this Rev.2 :30. 1985 (Box 124)
      - 2095. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Rydelle Labs. Zact Toothpaste. JSZA 5073 if you do this Rev.1 :30. 1985 (Box 124)
    - Rydelle Labs (continued), 1985-1986 (Box 125)
      - 2096. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Rydelle Labs. Fiberall Wafers. JSFI 5255 Better Tasting Way/Rev.2 New Super :15. 1985 (Box 125)
      - 2097. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Rydelle Labs. Fiberall. JSFW 6303 Split Screen/wafer :30. 1986 (Box 125)
    - Sun Banks, 1975-1976
      - 2098. MJ Productions. Sun Banks. SBT 5315-GE Corning Ware Rev.1 :30. 1975 (Box 125)
      - 2099. AFI. Sun Banks. SBT 5321-GE Sun Banker @4 :30. 1975 (Box 125)
      - 2100. FW Free. Sun Banks of Florida. SBT 6322-GE Helicopter :30. 1976 (Box 125)
      - 2101. FW Free. Sun Banks. 1976 (Box 125)
      - 2102. FW Free. Sun Banks of Florida. 1976 (Box 125)
      - 2103. FW Free. Sun Banks. Auto Loan (Cars in Hand). Undated (Box 125)
      - 2104. Sun Banks. Weber Grill. GRL 77108 IV Equinox Prod. Free. Undated (Box 125)
      - 2105. FW Free. Sun Banks of Florida. SBT 6322-GE Helicopter :30. 1976 (Box 125)
    - Miscellaneous A-D, 1985-1994and undated
      - 2106. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. AD Council. College of your Choice. 3 Spots. 1987 (Box 125)
      - 2107. Aid to the Higher Education Campaign. CNAE 7103 Give to the College of you choice :30; CNAE 7115 give to the college of your Choice :15. 1988 (Box 125)
      - 2108. Alpha Hydroxy Face Cream. looking for Wrinkles? :30 WCBS. 1994 (Box 125)
      - 2109. Chap LipStick Balm--9314252 NY :30 NBC; Blistex--9312322 NY :30 CBS; Softlips--9300153 NY :30 MTV. 1993 (Box 125)
      - 2110. Colonial Penn Demo Reel. 5 Spots. See Enclosed List. Undated (Box 125)
      - 2111. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. DBC. DBCO 4023 Marionette :60. 1985 (Box 125)
    - Miscellaneous E-Z, 1975-1996 and undated (Box 126)
      - 2112. Daniel & Charles. Emerson Film Transfer. :50. 1980 (Box 126)
      - 2113. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Bristol Myers Squibb. Foot Chargers. BMRZ 1013 Sneaker People :30. 1991 (Box 126)
      - 2114. Gotham Inc. Greg Louganis. 20/20 WABC :28. 1995 (Box 126)
      - 2115. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Head & Shoulders. Historical Reel w/ 23 Spots. See Enclosed List. 1993 (Box 126)
      - 2116. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. 6 spots. See Enclosed List. 1993 (Box 126)
      - 2117. Daniel & Charles. Lanvin. Jean Nate. LCJN 5303 Size 8 :30. 1975 (Box 126)
      - 2118. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. WM Free. National Airlines. 1986 (Box 126)
      - 2119. Daniel & Charles. OTB. Winners Circle Rev. :30. 1979 (Box 126)
      - 2120. Daniel & Charles. OTB. Winners Circle :30; pull Back Crowd Rev. Track. 1979 (Box 126)
      - 2121. Pepsi Presentation. National Historic Reel. 1978 (Box 126)
      - 2122. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Pert Plus Dandruff Historical Reel. 5 Spots. See Enclosed List. 1993 (Box 126)
      - 2123. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Score. Falling Leaves :30. 1994 (Box 126)
      - 2124. Gotham Inc. 3M/Ocelo. MMOC 4123 Baby Talk Rev. New CC :30. 1996 (Box 126)
      - 2125. A Eicoff and Co. 4 spots. See Enclosed List. Undated (Box 126)
      - 2126. William Esty Company Inc. Bob Sauer. Undated (Box 126)
      - 2127. Bob Sauer. Undated (Box 126)
    - Company presentation reels and agency reels, 1980-1991 (Box 127)
      - 2128. FW Free. Agency Presentation Reel Rev. 1980 (Box 127)
      - 2129. FW Free. Agency Reel Rev. II. 1981 (Box 127)
      - 2130. FW Free. New Business. NBL 815636 Film Transfer Master. 1981 (Box 127)
      - 2131. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Sample Reel. 14 spots. See Enclosed List.1986 (Box 127)
      - 2132. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Sample Reel. 15 Spots. See Enclosed List. 1986 (Box 127)
      - 2133. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Agency Reel. 12 spots. See Enclosed List. 1986 (Box 127)
      - 2134. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Reel. 14 spots. See Enclosed List. 1986 (Box 127)
      - 2135. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. New Business Reel. 12 Spots. See Enclosed List. 1989 (Box 127)
      - 2136. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. New Business Reel/ 8 Spots. See Enclosed List. 1989 (Box 127)
      - 2137. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Agency Reel. 1989 (Box 127)
      - 2138. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Agency Reel. See Enclosed List. 1989 (Box 127)
      - 2139. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. New Business Reel. 19 Spots. See Enclosed List. 1989 (Box 127)
      - 2140. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. See Enclosed List. Undated (Box 127)
      - 2141. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Composite Reel. 10 Spots. See Enclosed List. 1990 (Box 127)
      - 2142. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Presentation Reel. 1990 (Box 127)
      - 2143. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Agency Reel. See Enclosed List. 1991 (Box 127)
      - 2144. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Fat Lady Presentation. 1991 (Box 127)
    - Company presentation reels and agency reels (continued), 1992-1996 (Box 128)
      - 2145. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. New Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Logo. 1992 (Box 128)
      - 2146. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. New Business Reel 15 Spots. See Enclosed List. 1992 (Box 128)
      - 2147. Pfeifer Lopes Productions. Patrick Kelly Director. See Enclosed List. Undated (Box 128)
      - 2148. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Agency Open & Close :40 & :30. 1993 (Box 128)
      - 2149. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Agency Reel. :40 & :30. 1993 (Box 128)
      - 2150. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Agency Presentation Reel. See Enclosed List. 1993 (Box 128)
      - 2151. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. General Reel. See Enclosed List. 1993 (Box 128)
      - 2152. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Long General Reel. See Enclosed List. 1993 (Box 128)
      - 2153. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Agency Open & Close :40 & :30. 1993 (Box 128)
      - 2154. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. New Agency Opening. New Agency Closing. 1994 (Box 128)
      - 2155. Laurence Charles Free & Lawson. Peter Goldschmidt--Director. General Reel. 1994 (Box 128)
      - 2156. Gotham Inc. 8 Spots. See Enclosed List. 1995 (Box 128)
      - 2157. Gotham Inc. Full VPS. See Enclosed List. 1995 (Box 128)
      - 2158. Gotham Inc. Livamatics. See Enclosed List. 1995 (Box 128)
      - 2159. Gotham Inc. Steals/Animatics. See Enclosed List. 1995 (Box 128)
      - 2160. Gotham Inc. 14 spots. See Enclosed List. 1996 (Box 128)
    - Miscellaneous film reels,1983 and undated (Box 129)
      - 2161. Cadbury-Fry. Fry 3-60. open Wide :60 B/W P-16 2/17. Undated (Box 129)
      - 2162. Cadbury. Undated (Box 129)
      - 2163. Daniel & Charles. Clep. CLEP 6016 Classroom :60. College Entrance Examination Board. Joel Weiner of Bristol Myers. Undated (Box 129)
      - 2164. Fonda Corporation. Undated (Box 129)
      - 2165. GAF Snap Shots. Undated (Box 129)
      - 2166. Heublein Lancers. HLLW 3323 Fireplace Rev.1 :30. Undated (Box 129)
      - 2167. Laurence Charles Free. Savvy. BMSU 2503 Mirror Fantasy. :30. 16mm Color composite Reduce. 1983 (Box 129)
      - 2168. Daniel & Charles. Wohl Shoes. Clowns. Comp Color Print. Undated (Box 129)
- Slides and memorabilia, undated, 2 boxes
  Contains slides and memorabilia. Slides originally were housed both in binders and in boxes of loose slides. The slides are arranged alphabetically by product, as per original order in the binders; loose slides were organized in the same way.
  - Slides (Box 130)
    - Folder One: American Tobacco, Lucky Strike, Silkience, Cantario Tequila, Black & White Scotch, Black Velvet, Univac, National Airlines, DuBouchette, Heublien, LC&F Agency, Ancient Age, Asbach Brandy. Undated (Box 130)
    - Folder Two: Lamberti, McNaughton, Ole Tequila, Presidente, Simplicity, Spring Maid, Sport, True Story, Univac, Working Women, The Thin Edge. Undated (Box 130)
    - Folder Three: AARP, Adidas, Carlton, Lucky Strike, American Safety Razor, Baron's Chocolate, Ban, Bufferin, Comtrex. Undated (Box 130)
    - Folder Four: Comtrex (continued), The Thin Edge, Flame Glo, Sally Hansen, Endust, Dreyfus Corporation, Gortons, Black Velvet, Black and White Scotch, Club Cocktails, Irish Mist, Maidenform. Undated (Box 130)
    - Folder Five: Maidenform (continued), Mckinsey & Company, Tronolane, WNCN Radio, Seventeen, Working Women, Sport, True Stony, Carven, Cunard, GAF Roofing & Siding, GAF Slide Projector, GAF Darkroom Supplies, Madame Rochas, Bain de Soleil, Jean Nate, Supp Hose, National Airlines, Comtrex. Undated (Box 130)
    - Folder Six: Comtrex (continued), Ammens, Excedrin, Ban, Adidas, Jose Cuervo, Flame Glo, Sally Hansen, Rejuvia. Undated (Box 130)
    - Folder Seven: National Distillers Black Velvet Presentation, Lucky Strike Presentation, National Distillers Constant Change Presentation (1985), Extra Presentation Slides. General Mills Gortons Presentation (1985). Undated (Box 130)
    - Folder Eight: ABC, Adida, Air France, Almodrado, American Brands, American Lights, Ancient Age, Arpege. Undated (Box 130)
    - Folder Nine: Bab-O, Bain de Soleil, Ban, Bartons, Bazooka, Black and White Scotch, Black Velvet, Bufferin, Caffedrine, Carlton, Cepacol, Charter 10, Chateau Suisse, Cherry Heering, Colonial Penn Insurance, Comtrex, Condition, Dekuyper Peach Schnapps, Dexatrim, Dreyfus, DuBouchette. Undated (Box 131)
    - Folder Ten: Dunkin Donuts, Econo Lodge, Endust, Ensure, Esquire Socks, Faultless, Fiberall, Flame Glo, For Women First, GAF, Gortons, Hazel Bishop, Irish Mist, Jean Nate, Jose Cuervo, Journal Beauty, Keri. Undated (Box 131)
    - Folder Eleven: Lac-Hydrin, Lancers, Loews Hotels, McNaughton, Ma Griffe, Madame Rochas, Maidenform, Malibu, Marine Midland, Misty, Montclair. Undated (Box 131)
    - Folder Twelve: Murine Ear, Mr. Muscle, National Airlines, Nutrament, Office Temps, Pall Mall, Piping Rock, Porters, Premium Sun, Pre Sun, Quenches, Renuzit, Royal Crown, Sally Hansen, Selsun Blue, Shoney's, Simplicity, Sport, Suaza, Supp hose. Undated (Box 131)
    - Folder Thirteen: Taj Mahal, Tareyton, The Club Cocktails, The Hearst Corporation, The Thin Edge, Tronolane, True Story, Univac, Vanish, Weight Watchers, Windsor, Your Hit Parade, Unidentifiable slides. Undated (Box 131)
    - Folder Fourteen: Presentation Slides. Undated (Box 131)
    - Folder Fifteen: Presentation Slides (continued), Employee Photos, Newspaper Articles, Bristol Myers Blood Drive Ad, Photographs. Undated (Box 131)
  - Memorabilia
    - Two metal objects, one Engraved DC, the other engraved Daniel And Charles Inc. Advertising 261 Madison Ave, NY 16 MO 1-0200 (1971). Undated (Box 131)
- Print Advertisements, 1967-1997 and undated, 12 boxes
  Comprised of print advertisements which are organized alphabetically by product into two subseries by size: large and small format.
  - Large Format, 1967-1995 and undated
    - Abbot Treasures (Wigs). Undated (Box 132)
    - Adidas. 1984 (Box 132)
    - Air France. 1990 (Box 132)
    - Ban For Men. 1990 (Box 132)
    - Black Velvet. 1971-1983 (Box 132)
    - Black and White Scotch. 1975 (Box 132)
    - Camp Fire Girls. Undated (Box 132)
    - Dunkin' Donuts. 1967 (Box 132)
    - Golden Velvet. 1975 (Box 133)
    - The Heart Corporation. Undated (Box 133)
    - Madame Rochas. Undated (Box 133)
    - Marine Midland. Undated (Box 133)
    - McMaster's Whiskey. 1974 (Box 133)
    - National Airlines. Undated (Box 133)
    - Natural Glow. 1995 (Box 133)
    - Office Temporaries. Undated (Box 133)
    - RVC. Undated (Box 133)
    - Sally Hansen. 1994 (Box 133)
    - Seventeen. Undated (Box 133)
    - The Club Cocktails. Undated (Box 133)
    - True Story. Undated (Box 133)
    - Ultra Ban 5000. 1971-1972 (Box 133)
    - Ultra Ban Spray. 1973 (Box 133)
    - Article--NY Times Advertising A Great Respect for Instinct. 1968 (Box 133)
  - Small Format, 1969-1997 and undated
    - Adidas. 1983 (Box 134)
    - Advera. 1994 (Box 134)
    - Air France. 1986-1989 (Box 134)
    - American Tobacco. 1994 (Box 134)
    - Ammens. 1973 (Box 134)
    - Azura Wine. Undated (Box 134)
    - Bab-O. Undated (Box 134)
    - Ban: Ultra Ban, Ultra Ban 5000, Ultra Ban II, Ban Sensitive Touch, Ban Clear, Ban Basic, Ban Roll-On. 1972-1994 (Box 134)
    - Black and White Scotch. 1981 (Box 134)
    - Booths House of Lords. Undated (Box 134)
    - Bufferin. 1982-1994 (Box 134)
    - Black Velvet. 1972-1985 (Box 135)
    - Carlton Cigarettes (American Tobacco). 1994 (Box 136)
    - Cenenario Tequila. Undated (Box 136)
    - Chateau Suisse Chocolates. Undated (Box 136)
    - Cherry Heering. Undated (Box 136)
    - Cinzano. Undated (Box 136)
    - Clairol: Condition, Color hold, Frizz Control, Quick Lift. 1988-1996 (Box 136)
    - Color Plus. Undated (Box 136)
    - Comtrex. Undated (Box 136)
    - Congesprin. 1985 (Box 136)
    - Crown's Cigarettes (American Tobacco). 1992 (Box 136)
    - Daniel & Charles. Undated (Box 136)
    - Datril. 1969-1970 (Box 136)
    - Dunkin' Donuts. Undated (Box 136)
    - Endust. Undated (Box 137)
    - Esquire Socks. Undated (Box 137)
    - E Trade.Com. 1997 (Box 137)
    - Excedrin PM. 1980 (Box 137)
    - First Magazine. Undated (Box 137)
    - GAF Slide Projector. Undated (Box 137)
    - Gordons Gin. Undated (Box 137)
    - Gortons. Undated (Box 137)
    - Great Western Champagne. Undated (Box 137)
    - Halls. Undated (Box 137)
    - Hearst Corporation. 1985-1987 (Box 137)
    - Heublein: American Creame, Gold Rush, Sombrero, Long Island Ice Tea. 1983-1984 (Box 137)
    - Infusium 23. 1993 (Box 137)
    - Jean Nate. Undated (Box 137)
    - Jeremiah Weed Bourbon. 1980 (Box 137)
    - Jose Cuervo. 1973-1984 (Box 138)
    - Keri. 1984-1996 (Box 138)
    - Kwik Drain. Undated (Box 138)
    - Lac-Hydrin. 1988 (Box 139)
    - Lancers (Heublein). Undated (Box 139)
    - Liz Claiborne. 1996 (Box 139)
    - Loew's Hotels. Undated (Box 139)
    - Lucky Strike (American Tobacco). 1987 (Box 139)
    - Ma Griffe Perfume. Undated (Box 139)
    - Maidenform. Undated (Box 139)
    - Maison DuBouchette. Undated (Box 139)
    - Malibu Cigarettes. 1987 (Box 139)
    - Marine Midland. Undated (Box 139)
    - Maybelline. 1995 (Box 139)
    - Mckinsey & Co. Undated (Box 139)
    - Mercedes-Benz. 1998 (Box 139)
    - Misty Cigarettes (American Tobacco). 1994 (Box 139)
    - Mr. Muscle. 1974 (Box 139)
    - National Airlines. Undated (Box 139)
    - National Council on Crime & Delinquency. Undated (Box 139)
    - Naturistics Cosmetics. Undated (Box 139)
    - Nutrament. Undated (Box 139)
    - Ole Tequila. 1974 (Box 140)
    - Orajel. 1997 (Box 140)
    - Paul Masson Wines. 1989 (Box 140)
    - Pedro Domecq Brandy. 1978 (Box 140)
    - Premium Sun. Undated (Box 140)
    - Pre Sun. 1988 (Box 140)
    - Pronto Shampoo. 1997 (Box 140)
    - Regal Crown Lemon Drops. Undated (Box 140)
    - Renuzit. Undated (Box 140)
    - Ruberoid. Undated (Box 140)
    - Sally Hansen. 1994-1995 (Box 141)
    - Sauza Tequila. Undated (Box 141)
    - Selsun Blue. 1983-1993 (Box 141)
    - Shocking By Schiaparelli. Undated (Box 141)
    - Shoney's Restaurant. Undated (Box 141)
    - Sport. Undated (Box 142)
    - Taj Mahal Resort. Undated (Box 142)
    - Tampos. Undated (Box 142)
    - The Tine Edge. Undated (Box 142)
    - Tronolane. Undated (Box 142)
    - True Story. Undated (Box 143)
    - Univac. Undated (Box 143)
    - Vanish. Undated (Box 143)
    - Weight Watchers. 1970-1977 (Box 143)
    - Windjammer Cruises. Undated (Box 143)
    - Windsor Canadian Whiskey. 1985 (Box 143)
    - Working Women. 1979 (Box 143)
    - World Link Platinum Card. Undated (Box 143)
- Agency Information, 1930-1986 and undated, 1 box
  Contains information relating to Daniel & Charles and Laurence, Charles & Free. It also contains a price list for Gorton's Pew Fisheries Co.
  - Brochures and company history articles, 1962-1986 and undated (Box 144)
  - Gorton's Pew Fisheries, price list, 1930 (Box 144)
- Oversize
  - Miscellaneous Oversize (Oversize-folder Folder 1)